fatsoma.com 2012-05-01

# Fatsoma | Privacy Policy

Fatsoma Limited ("Fatsoma") is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. This privacy policy explains how we use the information we collect about you (or that you provide us with), how you can instruct us if you prefer to limit the use of that information and procedures that we have in place to safeguard your privacy. 

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the "Act"), the data controller is Fatsoma Limited of 3 The Stables, Wilmslow Road, East Didsbury, Manchester M20 5PG. 

1\. The information we collect and how we use it 

When you register for our service we need to know your name, email address, mobile number and date of birth. We gather this information to allow us to process your registration and to process any orders you may make. The relevant information is then used by us, our agents and sub-contractors to provide you with statements of your account and to communicate with you on any matter relating to the conduct of your account and the provision of the service in general.

We may also collect and process details of your visits to our site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access.

We may also use aggregate information and statistics for the purposes of monitoring website usage in order to help us develop the website and our services and may provide such aggregate information to third parties. These statistics will not include information that can be used to identify any individual. From time to time we may provide your information to our customer services agencies for research and analysis purposes so that we can monitor and improve the services we provide. We or our agents or sub-contractors may contact you by email, SMS, facsimile or telephone to ask for your feedback and comments on our services. If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data (the order form). We may also want to provide you with related information from third parties we think may be of interest to you. If you would rather not receive this information, please login to your account and update your privacy settings. 

If you have sent us a SMS, the originating number will be revealed to Fatsoma. We may store your telephone number so that we can SMS you updates or other offers. If you want to stop receiving such messages, SMS the word "STOP" to the reply number.

As part of your subscription to our service you will be sent emails which are relevant to your registration preferences. You have the ability to opt-out of these at any time by logging onto your account and updating your privacy settings. 

Fatsoma will not store credit or debit card information from payments made through our services. 

2\. Your control of personal information 

The information you submit is within your complete control. You have the ability to control to whom you make your profile visible to and which information is displayed. All of this can be controlled by logging into your account and updating your privacy settings. 

3\. IP Addresses and Cookies 

We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

For the same reason, we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help us to improve our site and to deliver a better and more personalised service. They enable us: 

  * To estimate our audience size and usage pattern. 
  * To store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise our site according to your individual interests. 
  * To speed up your searches. 
  * To recognise you when you return to our site. 

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our site. 

4\. Where we store your personal data 

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. Fatsoma will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted (using SSL technology). Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Athough we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. 

5\. Links 

Our website contains links to other websites. Please note that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites and advise you to read the privacy statements of each website you visit which collects personal information. 

6\. Disclosure of your information 

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 736 of the UK Companies Act 1985.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties: 

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If Fatsoma or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Fatsoma, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

7\. Updating your details 

All personal information entered into Fatsoma can be edited and changed by you at any time. Alterations can be made to within your administration area.   

8\. Your rights 

You have the right to cancel your membership at any time. This can be done by logging into your account and reviewing the cancellation options.

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [support@fatsoma.com](mailto:support@fatsoma.com)

9\. Your consent 

By submitting your information you consent to the use of that information as set out in this policy. If we change our privacy policy we will post the changes on this page, and may place notices on other pages of the website, so that you may be aware of the information we collect and how we use it at all times. Regularly reviewing this page will ensure that you are always aware of what information we collect and how we use it. Continued use of the service will signify that you agree to any such changes. Owing to the global nature of the internet infrastructure, the information you provide may be transferred in transit to countries outside the European Economic Area that do not have similar protections in place regarding your data and its use as set out in this policy. By submitting your information you consent to these transfers. 

10\. Access to Information 

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 GBP to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you. 

11\. How to contact Fatsoma 

We welcome your views about our website and our privacy policy. If you would like to contact us with any queries or comments please contact [support@fatsoma.com](mailto:support@fatsoma.com)
